<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome! on Vivian Nguyen</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome! on Vivian Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2024, Vivian Nguyen, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          <p><strong>Introduction</strong></p>
<p>Hi! My name is Vivian, and I am a senior at Harvard studying Statistics and Government.</p>
<p><strong>Current Location</strong></p>
<p>Cambridge, MA</p>
<p><strong>Skills</strong></p>
<p>Data analysis, predictive modeling</p>
<p><strong>Hobbies</strong></p>
<p>Chess, basketball, cookings</p>

          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Concern and Citizen Trust in Different Institutions</title>
      <link>/blog/121621-covid-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/121621-covid-trust/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          <h2 id="overview" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/121621-covid-trust/#overview" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Overview
</h2><p>February 2022</p>
<p>Note: I wrote this paper for Government 1372: Political Psychology, a
data science in the Harvard Government department. At this point, I was
gaining proficiency in R, but had not developed a sophisticated
understanding of statistics and causal inference yet. That said, this
paper was one of my first large data science projects, and was driven by
my newfound passion for applying data science techniques and programming
experience to (what I deem to be) relevant real-world problems. In Fall
2021, the pandemic was still a large public health concern, but the
public was battling a mixture of fear and desire for a return to
normalcy. I was very interested in what sources people trusted to
provide them information about the pandemic, and how that related to
their COVID anxieties – additionally, how does partisan alignment
interact with these variables?</p>
<h2 id="abstract" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/121621-covid-trust/#abstract" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Abstract
</h2><p>Over the past two years, the coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic has
disrupted the lives of billions of people, and has taken the lives of
millions. In that time, American citizens have reported notable levels
of concern about the pandemic (Albertson &amp; Gadarian, 2020). Trust in
government and officials is important in times of crisis, so how does
the new spike in anxiety relate to trust? This paper analyzes the
correlative relationship between concern about the pandemic and the
trust that Americans have in their government and other important
institutions. After observing 48 weeks of panel data of N ≈ 1,000 from
the KnowledgePanel, it is revealed that there is a positive correlation
between coronavirus concern and trust in state and federal government,
as well as the CDC and national health officials. Additionally, it is
shown that there exists a non-negligible factor of partisan identity in
the determination of trust in these important information sources – an
indicator of the pandemic’s unique politicization.</p>
<h2 id="trust-in-various-institutions" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/121621-covid-trust/#trust-in-various-institutions" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Trust in Various Institutions
</h2><p>Citizen trust in institutions, from health advisory bodies to different
levels of government, for relevant information is important for a
variety of reasons. During public health crises, trust in the advice of
medical experts is correlated with increased personal commitment to
safety measures that deter sickness (Goodwin et al., 2020). Increased
public trust in government allows for more ready acceptance of
containment policies, such as quarantine policies and medical testing,
during pandemics (Van Bavel et al., 2020). These COVID-19-related
insights are similar to those gathered during and after the 2014
Liberian Ebola Virus Disease epidemic: people who expressed low trust in
the government were significantly less likely to comply with
government-mandated social distancing policies, take precautions against
the virus, and support other virus control and containment policies
(Blair et al., 2017). Even away from the context of pandemics, the
relationship between institutional trust and adherence to policies
originating from or supported by that institution is rather intuitive;
previous literature has discussed the positive correlative relationship
between trust in government and law compliance (Marien &amp; Hooghe, 2001).</p>
<p>Not only do attitudes about COVID-19 policy and changes in trust have
important consequences for the success of public health initiatives and
planning, but they also may have an impact on electoral politics.
Increased citizen trust in government and health advisory could
contribute to previously studied “rally-round-the-flag” effects, where
politicians gain popular support during times of national hardship
(Mueller, 1970). Decreased trust in, perhaps paired with dissatisfaction
with, government officials and their pandemic policies could sway
election results against incumbents who are usually at an advantage
otherwise – a working paper by Noland and Zhang (2021) reports that if
Donald Trump handled the pandemic about 20 percent better, or had the
pandemic not happened at all, American citizen faith would not have
decreased to a level that allowed Joseph Biden to win the 2020 election
and claim the presidency.</p>
<h2 id="trust-as-an-outcome" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/121621-covid-trust/#trust-as-an-outcome" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Trust as an Outcome
</h2><p>Existing literature about trust in government, social trust, and the
effects of trust has highlighted the importance of trust in times of
crisis. In these works, trust in different institutions for important
information about relevant events has been treated as an independent
variable to assess outcomes such as compliance with public health safety
mandates, personal increased pandemic- hygiene behaviors, and impacts on
electoral politics. However, there exists much less work on what
influences citizen trust.</p>
<p>One such work comes from a 2010 study by Albertson and Gadarian, who
manipulated respondent anxiety to see its effects on trust as an outcome
variable. The researchers hypothesized that anxiety can increase or
decrease citizen trust in different experts, but more specifically, a
threat from an external place, far from the government’s jurisdiction,
including pandemics, was predicted to lead to increased anxiety that
lended itself to increased trust in governmental actors. As outlined in
their report on the study, this hypothesis was supported by system
justification theory (Jost, 2020), which posits that people cope with
negative events by throwing their support behind and faith in existing
systems, such as the government and institutions that are widely
recognized. At a basic level, this is reasonable, as it is expected that
anxious people would look to trusted officials for information in times
of crisis and uncertainty.</p>
<p>After establishing this theoretical framework, the researchers tested
their hypothesis by comparing participants’ trust in different experts
(Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, U.S. President, friends in
the medical field, and more) between the control group and the treatment
group, where respondents were treated with H1N1 (“swine flu”; influenza
A virus pandemic in 2009 and 2010) anxiety. Trust in various experts to
provide information about the H1N1 pandemic was reported on scales
ranging from “not at all” to “a great deal.” For most of the experts the
study asked respondents about, the treatment group reported more trust
than did the control group. This effect was clear for respected “expert”
federal health organizations – anxiety about the H1N1 virus led
respondents to trust the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention
(CDC) and the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services more to
provide information about H1N1. Interestingly, the treatment did not
cause significant increases in trust in public government officials like
Barack Obama, perhaps because he was not perceived to have relevant
expertise on the public health crisis despite speaking about it multiple
times.<br>
A decade ago, it was intuitive that anxiety about a public health crisis
would lead Americans to trust in federal health agencies to provide
relevant information about the pandemic more. But as Albertson and
Gadarian have aptly pointed out in their 2020 Washington Post analysis
of the coronavirus in the United States, COVID-19 is different from H1N1
in that it is heavily politicized and treated as a partisan issue. With
partisan divides underpinning Americans’ emotional response to pandemic
policies, the pandemic’s effects on anxiety and trust are no longer
clear nor intuitive. Do COVID-anxious people place their trust in health
experts? Does partisanship shape respondent trust in institutions and
experts more than actual anxiety?</p>
<p>In this research paper, I aim to analyze the correlative relationship
between anxious concern about COVID-19 and trust in different
institutions (the CDC, national health advisors, the federal government,
and the state government). I also compare this relationship to the
relationship between partisanship and the different trust responses to
determine if politicization of the pandemic has gone so far as to make
party identification more important than concern about the virus in
deciding citizens’ trust in important pandemic policymaking
institutions.</p>
<h2 id="hypotheses" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/121621-covid-trust/#hypotheses" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Hypotheses
</h2><p><em>H</em><!-- raw HTML omitted -->1<!-- raw HTML omitted --> : Concern about COVID-19 is positively correlated with
trust in all four bodies (CDC, national health advisors, federal
government, and state government).</p>
<p><em>H</em><!-- raw HTML omitted -->2<!-- raw HTML omitted --> : Partisan identification (as Democrat or Republican)
has at least as much predictive power as COVID-19 concern in determining
respondent trust in the COVID-19 information sources.</p>
<p><em>H</em><!-- raw HTML omitted -->2.1<!-- raw HTML omitted --> : Respondents who identify as Democrats are more
likely to trust the CDC for pandemic information than those who identify
as Republicans.</p>
<h2 id="the-axiosipsos-coronavirus-index" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/121621-covid-trust/#the-axiosipsos-coronavirus-index" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>The Axios/Ipsos Coronavirus Index
</h2><p>To test these hypotheses, Lucy and I used data from the Axios/Ipsos
Coronavirus Index, a weekly survey fielded from the Ipsos
KnowledgePanel. The Ipsos KnowledgePanel is a longstanding online panel
of about 60,000 United States members from diverse populations,
including racial minorities, veterans, people with disabilities,
adolescents, LGBTQ+ people, gun owners/ households, and more.
Specifically, (we) analyzed the data from respondents surveyed from
March 13, 2020 to June 28, 2021 from Axios/Ipsos Poll Waves 1 through
Wave 48, which had weekly sample sizes of about 1,000 adults.</p>
<p>Each week, the poll collected responses about Americans’ behaviors, risk
perceptions, attitudes about COVID-19. A few questions were of interest
to me, regarding (1) COVID-19 concern, (2) trust in the federal
government, (3) trust in the state government, (4) trust in the CDC, (5)
and trust in national public health officials. These questions were
asked as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>“How concerned are you, if at all, about the coronavirus or COVID-19
outbreak?”</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>Extremely concerned (b) Very concerned (c) Somewhat concerned</li>
<li>Not very concerned (e) Not at all concerned</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>“How much trust do you have in [the federal government] to provide
you with accurate information about coronavirus or COVID-19?”</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>A great deal (b) A fair amount</li>
<li>Not very much (d) None at all</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>“How much trust do you have in [your state government] to provide
you with accurate information about coronavirus or COVID-19?” Same
answer options as above</li>
<li>“How much trust do you have in [the Centers for Disease Control, or
CDC] to provide you with accurate information about coronavirus or
COVID-19?” Same answer options as above</li>
<li>“How much trust do you have in [national public health officials]
to provide you with accurate information about coronavirus or
COVID-19?” Same answer options as above</li>
</ul>
<p>We also used the responses to demographic questions as control
variables, including respondent age, education level, gender, income,
and party identification.</p>
<p>We recoded the COVID concern, trust, and some control variables to make
them more readable, where higher values corresponded with higher
concern, trust, age, etc. For the party variable, a value of 0
corresponded with Democrats, 1 with Independents, and 2 with
Republicans.</p>
<h2 id="methods" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/121621-covid-trust/#methods" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Methods
</h2><p>To test <em>H</em><!-- raw HTML omitted -->1<!-- raw HTML omitted --> , “Concern about COVID-19 is positively
correlated with trust in all four bodies (CDC, national health advisors,
federal government, and state government),” I ran four linear regression
models, each with one of the four trust variables as the outcome
variable and dependent variables such as COVID-19 concern, age,
education, ethnicity, gender, and party. To show the regression results,
I plotted the regression coefficients of each dependent variable for
each trust outcome variable. This analytical method and plot combination
was chosen for this hypothesis because the linear regression modelling
reveals a presence, or lack of, positive correlative relationship
between each trust outcome variable and explanatory variables such as
COVID concern. The coefficient plot visually demonstrates the
relationships between each predictor variable and respondents’ trust,
including the effect of COVID concern on trust.</p>
<p>To test <em>H</em><!-- raw HTML omitted -->2<!-- raw HTML omitted --> , “Partisan identification has at least as much
predictive power as COVID-19 concern in determining respondent trust in
the COVID-19 information sources,” I again ran the four linear
regression models. In order to compare the ability of party
identification versus COVID concern to explain the variance in trust in
different institutions and actors, I used the <code>scale()</code> function to
standardize the previously different scales of the explanatory
variables. This method is appropriate to test <em>H</em><!-- raw HTML omitted -->2<!-- raw HTML omitted --> because it
allows direct comparison of the regression coefficients associated with
COVID concern and party identification. Thus, the variable tied to the
larger scaled coefficient can be interpreted as the dependent variable
with more predictive power for trust in coronavirus information sources.</p>
<p>To test <em>H</em><!-- raw HTML omitted -->2.1<!-- raw HTML omitted --> , “Respondents who identify as Democrats are
more likely to trust the CDC than those who identify as Republicans,” I
plotted the predicted trust in the CDC for Democrats versus the
predicted CDC trust for Republicans using the <code>predict()</code> function. This
analytical methodology was chosen because it reveals respondents’
predicted trust in the CDC by party.</p>
<h2 id="results" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/121621-covid-trust/#results" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Results
</h2><p>For all trust outcomes (trust in the federal government, trust in state
governments, trust in the CDC, and trust in national health officials),
changes in COVID concern, education, and party were found to have
statistically significant effects on trust. The plots below show the
regression coefficients of each predictor variable for the trust outcome
variables, with 95% confidence intervals around each coefficient
estimate.</p>
<p>The control variables of gender, ethnicity, and age had near-zero
coefficients in each model.<br>


  
  Predictor Variable Regression Coefficients for
Trust

  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  


  <figure>
    <a href="/blog/121621-covid-trust/images/plot1.png">
      <picture>
        <source
          media="(max-width: 376px)"
          srcset="/blog/121621-covid-trust/images/plot1_hua89c74c4b55160d22ee8e60444fc945e_221423_500x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(max-width: 992px)"
          srcset="/blog/121621-covid-trust/images/plot1_hua89c74c4b55160d22ee8e60444fc945e_221423_800x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(max-width: 1400px)"
          srcset="/blog/121621-covid-trust/images/plot1_hua89c74c4b55160d22ee8e60444fc945e_221423_1200x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(min-width: 1600px)"
          srcset="/blog/121621-covid-trust/images/plot1_hua89c74c4b55160d22ee8e60444fc945e_221423_1500x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <img
          alt="Predictor Variable Regression Coefficients for
Trust"
          title="Predictor Variable Regression Coefficients for
Trust"
          src="images/plot1.png"
          height="1206"
          width="1662"
          loading="lazy"
        />
      </picture>
    </a>
    <figcaption class="text-sm italic">
      Predictor Variable Regression Coefficients for
Trust
    </figcaption>
  </figure>


</p>
<p>For trust in the federal government, the regression coefficient of COVID
concern was 0.112, meaning that holding all else constant, an increase
of 1 in COVID concern (which is on a scale of 1 through 4) was
accompanied by an increase in federal government trust by 0.112 (on a
scale of 1 through 4). For the remaining regression model results, an
increase of 1 in COVID concern meant: an increase of 0.209 in state
government trust, an increase of 0.290 in CDC trust, and an increase of
0.281 in national health official trust. These results from the linear
regression models and coefficient plots support <em>H</em><!-- raw HTML omitted -->1<!-- raw HTML omitted -->, as it
is shown that across all four measures of trust, concern about COVID-19
is positively (and statistically significantly) correlated with trust.
These results are consistent with previous research that examined the
relationship between increased anxiety about public health issues and
increased trust in health and public officials.</p>
<p>Figure 1 reveals that party and COVID concern have the regression
coefficients of the largest magnitude. Which is more impactful in
regards to trust? To directly compare the regression coefficients of
COVID concern and party identification as they contribute to changes in
trust, the linear regressions were run again, but this time the
aforementioned predictor variables were scaled. The previously different
scales – 1 through 4 for concern and 1 through 3 for party – are now
standardized, making the variables’ regression coefficients directly
comparable.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>From Figure 2, which presents the scaled regression coefficients of
COVID concern and party alongside other control variable coefficients,
it is evident that for each trust measure, COVID concern is tied to a
larger scaled coefficient than party ID. The larger coefficient of COVID
concern indicates that when on the same scale as party identification,
COVID concern affects respondent trust in the different expert sources
more than party does. Thus, contrary to <em>H</em><!-- raw HTML omitted -->2<!-- raw HTML omitted -->, COVID concern
actually has more predictive power than party identification in
determining respondent trust across the information sources. This
finding was rather intriguing, as it revealed the truth of a balance
that seemed could have tipped either way (towards coronavirus concern or
partisan identity); the perceived politicization of the COVID-19
pandemic in the United States made it seem plausible that partisanship
determined trust in relevant public health officials to an even larger
degree than concern about the pandemic itself. Evidently, though
partisanship had some effect on trust (as party identification had
notably large regression coefficients in relation to the trust outcome
variables), it was still trumped by the effect of concern about the
pandemic.</p>
<p>Further examining the non-negligible relationship between trust in
officials about COVID-19 information and partisanship reveals that
different party identification is tied to to different levels of
predicted trust in the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>Figure 3 shows the predicted level of trust in the CDC by members of
each party as COVID concern rises. Both parties appear to follow the
same trend of increased trust in the Centers for Disease Control and
Prevention as COVID concern increases in respondents, but CDC trust
begins and ends at higher values for Democrats. <em>H</em><!-- raw HTML omitted -->2.1<!-- raw HTML omitted --> stated
that “Respondents who identify as Democrats are more likely to trust the
CDC than those who identify as Republicans” and was supported, as
Democrats are shown to have higher predicted trust in the CDC than
Republicans across all values of COVID concern. This result is somewhat
expected, as Democrats have been more worried about containing the
coronavirus pandemic and open to the advisory of health advisory such as
the works that come from the CDC. Additionally, it is expected that
Republicans would have less comparative trust in the CDC due to Donald
Trump’s attitudes towards the organization: U.S. President from 2016 to
late 2020 and popular amongst Republicans, Trump publicly undercut the
credibility of the CDC several times, claiming the organization’s
vaccine announcements were “just incorrect information,” calling the
Director “confused,” and contradicting the advisory messages put out by
the CDC.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/121621-covid-trust/#conclusion" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Conclusion
</h2><p>In recent years, policymakers and health organizations worldwide have
been working to end the coronavirus pandemic that began in late 2019.
One of the important factors in this effort is citizen trust in public
health information. Thus, this paper aimed to analyze the correlative
relationship between the increased concern Americans have felt about the
pandemic and their trust in different public bodies of information,
including in the federal and state government, Centers for Disease
Control and Prevention, and national health advisers. It was
hypothesized, and confirmed, that trust was positively correlated with
concern across all four measures of trust. Furthermore, it was shown
that contrary to the second hypothesis, despite the intense
politicization of the COVID-19 pandemic, partisan identity still was not
a stronger predictor of trust than actual concern about the pandemic.
However, partisanship still had some predictive power for trust in
institutions like the CDC, with Democrat respondents being more likely
to report higher levels of trust in the CDC than Republicans, confirming
the final hypothesis.</p>
<p>These hypotheses were tested using linear regression models and
prediction models of data from the Axios/Ipsos Coronavirus Index. This
study can be extended and improved upon with randomized controlled
methodology, so that the causal, rather than correlative, relationship
between pandemic anxiety and trust in important information sources can
be uncovered.</p>
<p>This project makes contributions to the growing body of work on the
study of the COVID-19 pandemic, American behaviors in crises, the effect
of politicization, and the relationship between anxiety and political
behavior and attitudes. The pandemic has been handled by many political
actors and thus, attitudes related to pandemic policy and information
have some political charge, but individual concern about the pandemic in
regards to the wellbeing of loved ones and themselves still remains the
most significant factor in determining trust in relevant entities –
citizen trust, which was previously established to be important
emotional capital in areas ranging from pandemic containment to
electoral politics, has not been perverted by partisanship yet.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<p>[1] Albertson, &amp; Gadarian, S. K. (2015). Anxious politics: Democratic
Citizenship in a Threatening World. Cambridge University Press.</p>
<p>[2] Albertson, B., &amp; Gadarian, S. K. (2020, March 20). Analysis | This
is who Americans trust about coronavirus information. The Washington
Post. Retrieved from <a href="https://www.washingtonp" title="https://www.washingtonp" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.washingtonp</a>
ost.com/politics/2020/03/20/were-all-anxious-about-pandemic-who-do-americans-want-hear</p>
<p>[3] Blair, R. A., Morse, B. S., &amp; Tsai, L. L. (2017). Public health
and public trust: Survey evidence from the Ebola Virus Disease epidemic
in Liberia. Social Science &amp; Medicine (1982), 172, 89–97.
<a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2016.11.016" title="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2016.11.016" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2016.11.016</a></p>
<p>[4] Goodwin, R., Wiwattanapantuwong, J., Tuicomepee, A., Suttiwan, P.,
&amp; Watakakosol, R. (2020). Anxiety and public responses to covid-19:
Early Data from Thailand. Journal of Psychiatric Research, 129, 118–121.
<a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychires.2020.06.026" title="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychires.2020.06.026" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychires.2020.06.026</a></p>
<p>[5] Jost, J. T. (2020). A theory of system justification. Harvard
University Press.</p>
<p>[6] Marien, &amp; Hooghe, M. (2011). Does political trust matter? An
empirical investigation into the relation between political trust and
support for law compliance. European Journal of Political Research,
50(2), 267–291. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1475-6765.2010.01930.x" title="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1475-6765.2010.01930.x" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1475-6765.2010.01930.x</a></p>
<p>[7] Mueller, J. E. (1970). Presidential Popularity from Truman to
Johnson. The American Political Science Review, 64(1), 18–34.
<a href="https://doi.org/10.2307/1955610" title="https://doi.org/10.2307/1955610" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://doi.org/10.2307/1955610</a></p>
<p>[8] Noland, M., &amp; Zhang, Y. E. (2021). Covid-19 and the 2020 US
presidential election: Did the pandemic cost Donald Trump reelection?
SSRN Electronic Journal. <a href="https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3807255" title="https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3807255" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3807255</a></p>
<p>[9] Van Bavel, Baicker, K., Boggio, P. S., Capraro, V., Cichocka, A.,
Cikara, M., Crockett, M. J., Crum, A. J., Douglas, K. M., Druckman, J.
N., Drury, J., Dube, O., Ellemers, N., Finkel, E. J., Fowler, J. H.,
Gelfand, M., Han, S., Haslam, S. A., Jetten, J., … Willer, R. (2020).
Using social and behavioural science to support COVID-19 pandemic
response. Nature Human Behaviour, 4(5), 460–471.
<a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-020-0884-z" title="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-020-0884-z" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-020-0884-z</a></p>

          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision-making and Heuristics</title>
      <link>/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          <h1 id="introduction" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/#introduction" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Introduction
</h1><p>This is the first Data Exploration task of Fall 2021! Welcome. This week, my classmates of Government 1372 (Political Psychology) and I worked with our in-class survey results to observe how susceptible we are to cognitive biases and discuss how that may affect our decision-making.</p>
<h1 id="data-details" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/#data-details" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Data Details
</h1><p>*File Name: bias_data.csv</p>
<p>*Source: These data are from last week&rsquo;s in-class survey.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Variable Name</th>
<th>Variable Description</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>id</td>
<td>Unique ID for each respondent</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>rare_disease_prog</td>
<td>From the rare disease problem, the program chosen by the respondent (either &lsquo;Program A&rsquo; or &lsquo;Program B&rsquo;)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>rare_disease_cond</td>
<td>From the rare disease problem, the framing condition to which the respondent was assigned (either &lsquo;save&rsquo; or &lsquo;die&rsquo;)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>linda</td>
<td>From the Linda problem, the option the respondent thought most probable, either &ldquo;teller&rdquo; or &ldquo;teller and feminist&rdquo;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>cab</td>
<td>From the cab problem, the respondent&rsquo;s estimate of the probability the car was blue</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>gender</td>
<td>One of &ldquo;man&rdquo;, &ldquo;woman&rdquo;, &ldquo;non-binary&rdquo;, or &ldquo;other&rdquo;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>year</td>
<td>Year at Harvard</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>college_stats</td>
<td>Indicator for whether or not the respondent has taken a college-level statistics course</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h1 id="the-linda-problem" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/#the-linda-problem" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>The Linda Problem
</h1><p>&ldquo;Linda is 31 years old, single, outspoken, and very bright. She majored in accounting. As a student, she was deeply concerned with issues of women&rsquo;s rights, and also studied economics.</p>
<p>Which is more probable: Linda is a bank teller, or Linda is both a teller and feminist?&rdquo;</p>
<p>70.59% of the class answered this question correctly. While the majority of our class was able to choose the right answer, many people in general tend to choose the wrong option. This occurs because many people think that given information about someone, the information makes something more likely about them. When we know that Linda is interested in social activism, we think it is not surprising for her to be a feminist. Most people, however, are not aware of the probability principles of the Linda question &ndash; or they simply ignore the principle because the seemingly logical connection between what we know about Linda and what could be true is too convincing in the moment.</p>
<h1 id="the-cab-problem" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/#the-cab-problem" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>The Cab Problem
</h1><p>&ldquo;A cab was involved in a hit and run accident at night. Two cab companies, the Green and the Blue, operate in the city. 85% of the cabs in the city are Green and 15% are Blue.</p>
<p>A witness identified the cab as Blue. The court tested the reliability of the witness under the same circumstances that existed on the night of the accident and concluded that the witness correctly identified each one of the two colours 80% of the time and failed 20% of the time.</p>
<p>What is the probability that the cab involved in the accident was Blue rather than Green knowing that this witness identified it as Blue?&rdquo;</p>
<p>That said, the most common response was 0.8.</p>
<h2 id="extension" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/#extension" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Extension
</h2><p>So then, what attributes of the respondents might affect how they answered the Linda problem and why?</p>
<p>I would guess that college statistic education, age, responses to the cab question could correlate to students&rsquo; answers to the Linda question.</p>
<p>To explore this question, I first examined the crosstable of responses to the Linda question sorted by respondents who had taken a college statistics course versus those who had not.</p>
<p>

  
  Linda

  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  


  <figure>
    <a href="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindastats.png">
      <picture>
        <source
          media="(max-width: 376px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindastats_huf0adbb658403c13ad779a561646f55b0_46616_500x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(max-width: 992px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindastats_huf0adbb658403c13ad779a561646f55b0_46616_800x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(max-width: 1400px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindastats_huf0adbb658403c13ad779a561646f55b0_46616_1200x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(min-width: 1600px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindastats_huf0adbb658403c13ad779a561646f55b0_46616_1500x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <img
          alt="Linda"
          title="Linda"
          src="images/lindastats.png"
          height="493"
          width="691"
          loading="lazy"
        />
      </picture>
    </a>
    <figcaption class="text-sm italic">
      Linda
    </figcaption>
  </figure>


</p>
<p>From this table, we see that students with at least some formal statistics knowledge are more likely to answer the Linda question correctly. 75.9% of statistics students correctly answered that Linda was more likely to be only a teller, while only 61.3% of non-statistics students were able to do so. Despite the non-statistics-student group being much smaller than its counterpart group (31 versus 54 people), both groups contain a similar quantity of students who responded incorrectly – 12 and 13. From these proportions, we can see that respondents who have not taken a college-level statistics course are more likely to use the attribution substitution shortcut to form conclusions about who Linda is. Because the question provides that Linda is outspoken about issues of activism and seems liberal, a heuristic that leads observers to a statistical fallacy – believing that Linda must then be a feminist too – is readily available. Observers don’t actually know if Linda is a feminist, so they substitute the attribute in question with more known ones, such as her activism. However, if observers pay closer attention, their System 2 may remind them of the statistical principle that states “a conjunction of two events can’t be more probable than either of the events occurring by itself.” Of course, previous students of statistics are more likely to remember this principle before allowing their intuitive heuristics to decide Linda’s character for them.</p>
<p>Understanding that students with some statistical background fare better when facing heuristics pitfalls, I wanted to explore the relationship, if any, between responses to the Linda question and responses to the blue cab question. How likely is it that the cab is actually blue? Is Linda a teller with feminist hobbies? These questions are hard to answer with certainty, so do respondents use heuristics to form conclusions about these questions? To look at how these questions’ responses interact, I plotted the Linda responses versus the blue cab responses. I also graphed a vertical line at the actual, statistically correct probability of the identified cab being a blue cab in navy blue, p = 0.41.</p>
<p>

  
  Linda Responses

  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  


  <figure>
    <a href="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindadot.png">
      <picture>
        <source
          media="(max-width: 376px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindadot_hu6e1f86d9094446ff8b3abc1c19c9465b_104994_500x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(max-width: 992px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindadot_hu6e1f86d9094446ff8b3abc1c19c9465b_104994_800x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(max-width: 1400px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindadot_hu6e1f86d9094446ff8b3abc1c19c9465b_104994_1200x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(min-width: 1600px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindadot_hu6e1f86d9094446ff8b3abc1c19c9465b_104994_1500x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <img
          alt="Linda Responses"
          title="Linda Responses"
          src="images/lindadot.png"
          height="889"
          width="1497"
          loading="lazy"
        />
      </picture>
    </a>
    <figcaption class="text-sm italic">
      Linda Responses
    </figcaption>
  </figure>


</p>
<p>From this plot, I noticed that those who labeled Linda “teller and feminist” tended to believe that there was a high likelihood that the cab was actually blue. Some respondents who correctly answered the Linda question also thought that the cab was blue, with many responses concentrated over the p = 0.70 mark. However, the “teller” group had many more responses on the lower end of the cab probabilities than the “teller and feminist” group. This indicates to me that the former group perhaps had some intuition that the cab was less likely blue than the question initially would suggest. I then plotted the same data as a bar graph to get another visual.</p>
<p>

  
  Linda x Cab

  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  


  <figure>
    <a href="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindabar.png">
      <picture>
        <source
          media="(max-width: 376px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindabar_hua57cd099bb044b84f08c5a192f023dc4_109437_500x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(max-width: 992px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindabar_hua57cd099bb044b84f08c5a192f023dc4_109437_800x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(max-width: 1400px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindabar_hua57cd099bb044b84f08c5a192f023dc4_109437_1200x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(min-width: 1600px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindabar_hua57cd099bb044b84f08c5a192f023dc4_109437_1500x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <img
          alt="Linda x Cab"
          title="Linda x Cab"
          src="images/lindabar.png"
          height="865"
          width="1416"
          loading="lazy"
        />
      </picture>
    </a>
    <figcaption class="text-sm italic">
      Linda x Cab
    </figcaption>
  </figure>


</p>
<p>The majority of people who were correctly skeptical of the blue car ID are those at or near the navy vertical line. Those to the left of the vertical line also seem to have reason to believe that the likelihood of the car actually being blue is much closer to the base rate than 0.80, the most common response from our survey. As shown in the segmented bar graph, most of the respondents who were able to show correct or somewhat promising reasoning about the blue cab problem (those at or to the left of the vertical line shown at 0.41) are part of the “teller” group, the same students who answered the Linda question correctly. I believe there is a correlation between the ability of respondents to respond correctly to the Linda problem and the ability of those same respondents to answer the cab question correctly. Because both Linda and the cab are questions that require some statistical knowledge to figure out, the responses to these questions may be related in a way that is worth investigating. Though I do not know how to properly look at the correlation between these responses using R yet, I attempted to observe that using a crosstable of blue-cab-probability-responses versus linda-feminist-status-responses next.</p>
<p>

  
  Linda x Cab 2

  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  


  <figure>
    <a href="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindacab.png">
      <picture>
        <source
          media="(max-width: 376px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindacab_hu9613546ec1374d025df7bc59321f7a0b_90322_500x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(max-width: 992px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindacab_hu9613546ec1374d025df7bc59321f7a0b_90322_800x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(max-width: 1400px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindacab_hu9613546ec1374d025df7bc59321f7a0b_90322_1200x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <source
          media="(min-width: 1600px)"
          srcset="/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/images/lindacab_hu9613546ec1374d025df7bc59321f7a0b_90322_1500x0_resize_q75_h2_box_3.webp"
        />

        <img
          alt="Linda x Cab 2"
          title="Linda x Cab 2"
          src="images/lindacab.png"
          height="582"
          width="861"
          loading="lazy"
        />
      </picture>
    </a>
    <figcaption class="text-sm italic">
      Linda x Cab 2
    </figcaption>
  </figure>


</p>
<p>Sorting the responses to the cab question into intervals of width 0.10, I observed how often respondents in each interval answered the cab question correctly (T = “teller”) versus incorrectly (TaF = “teller and feminist”). As hypothesized, respondents who were correctly suspicious of the blue ID of the car (so those who answered that the cab was only ~30-50% likely to be blue) were often the same group of people to know that Linda was more likely only a teller. The higher cab guesses, p = 0.8 and up, were more often wrong about Linda. Thus, I conclude that if a respondent ignores the base rate of blue cabs and responds with a higher probability (such as p = 0.8 or p = 0.85), then they are more likely to use attribute substitution to answer the Linda question than respondents who were able to statistically reason their way to the correct estimate for the cab color’s likelihood.</p>
<p>Investigating the traits or behaviors of respondents who answer the Linda question correctly or incorrectly was very interesting to me as an initial data exercise. The data gathered from our class survey confirms, especially with the cab problem, that humans are not always able to use our System 2’s and logically reason through confusing questions. What makes respondents more likely to answer the Linda question correctly? After this investigation, I understand that college statistics background has some pull. I also understand now that the respondents’ ability to answer different challenging questions, such as the blue cab one, may indicate their ability to statistically reason and answer our Linda question of interest. Probability and statistics skills are not the most intuitive to most humans, and yet the ability to leverage them has shown to be significant in our class’ responses to seemingly simple survey questions.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<p>[1] Kahneman (2003)</p>

          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorem Markdownum</title>
      <link>/blog/lorem-markdownum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/lorem-markdownum/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          
            <p>
              <img align="left" hspace="5" src="/blog/lorem-markdownum/images/aaron-burden-AXqMy8MSSdk-unsplash_hubbfe6d9ef68d83c7b8ac0a6954f2118c_2893721_0x550_resize_q100_h2_box.webp"/>
            </p>
          
          <h2 id="amens-nitentior-vires" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/lorem-markdownum/#amens-nitentior-vires" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Amens nitentior vires
</h2><p>Lorem markdownum Argo est praebebant Andros erat, tibi parte montibus erunt
venis tacita spernimus more. Olim erat Aiax <em>dixi factas</em> potens. Perque natus
ipsa <a href="http://fugias.com/illa.php" title="potenti" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">potenti</a>; nunc parte precor in mortalis manant
bellica, umbrosaque et. Inrita videtur regnum, in est vulnere inductae Ilion et
feruntur Latiae famulus nec dederat uteroque lenita <strong>fraternaque horrenda
omnia</strong>.</p>
<ol>
<li>Maris Circe victum suggerit et conscia dixit</li>
<li>Habes et undis carinae fundae lilia coniecit</li>
<li>Tot nomine ire tot fassusque nobis ad</li>
<li>Geminas iugales mille et ingenium magna agitantem</li>
<li>Nemo quae sedemque</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="iunone-theseius-abstulit-morabar-mersis" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/lorem-markdownum/#iunone-theseius-abstulit-morabar-mersis" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Iunone Theseius abstulit morabar mersis
</h2><p>Isto supremo, genitor Phoronidos, honos ibi lacus saepe rogato properus: sum an
vetantis. Non Marte praecessit fistula dentibus non; in in quoque passaque. Non
tectis ferox. Non ille et nomine vel aliisque tollens illic <strong>morae virga</strong>
repugnat: a lateri Achillem me illum. Acoetes potentior matrique occasu laborum
sua letum Inachidas irata cognoscere quae dum prohibent est exilio.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-go" data-lang="go"><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#ff79c6">package</span> main
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#ff79c6">import</span> <span style="color:#f1fa8c">&#34;fmt&#34;</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#8be9fd;font-style:italic">func</span> <span style="color:#50fa7b">main</span>() {
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    fmt.<span style="color:#50fa7b">Println</span>(<span style="color:#f1fa8c">&#34;Hello, World!&#34;</span>)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>}
</span></span></code></pre></div><h2 id="haec-posuitque-altorum" class="link-owner">
  <a href="/blog/lorem-markdownum/#haec-posuitque-altorum" class="link">
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ionicon" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><title>Link</title><path fill="none" d="M208 352h-64a96 96 0 010-192h64M304 160h64a96 96 0 010 192h-64M163.29 256h187.42" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke-width="36"/></svg>
  </a>Haec posuitque altorum
</h2><p>Studiosius auctoribus secuta remos partu, non animam aequalique haec tum.
<strong>Tabellas vidit</strong> ventus postquam ab scelus pollue canoro. Natus ede semina
illa canitiemque illac; haec illa <strong>Hylonome</strong> ille haut deos. Pares accepta
recipit, visaque litora, lacrimasque fovit, et Aeacus.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>if (carrierLossyLed.digital.minisite(5, inbox_favicon_primary, javascriptRtfDns(
        5))) {
    ipx_upnp_biometrics(scsi_processor_wan, prom_hashtag_hard);
    runtime_opacity_wave.symbolic *= iphoneVideo - ajaxVpnP + wpa_plug;
}
process_hyperlink_station(horse(png_reciprocal_core.memory_p(gps, flash),
        url_restore_personal));
storage_mode.optical = 1;
</code></pre><p>Hiems <strong>Athamanta nequeunt</strong> ni nunc sanguine; imo sine solutum, virgo gurgitis
vernat vaticinatus planxere. Terris nam caeco uti multos imas saepe, Iuno dea
tremit viros Iove sub. Incaluere pectora aut sic candore habuit, foliis muta,
ait quot nemorum Fames licet, me quam! Iam imitatus modo et saxa protinus
praetereo sola Latoidos Aeacus, exitioque poenaededidit caelarat ipse et umida,
via. Lenimen Busirin, Arctos eo citaeque et artificum quidem fugit <strong>magna</strong>,
ubi.</p>
<hr>
<p>Image: <a href="https://unsplash.com/@aaronburden" title="https://unsplash.com/@aaronburden" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://unsplash.com/@aaronburden</a></p>

          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          


<div id="r-markdown" class="section level1">
<h1>R Markdown</h1>
<p>This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see <a href="http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com" class="uri">http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com</a>.</p>
<p>You can embed an R code chunk like this:</p>
<pre class="r"><code>summary(cars)
##      speed           dist       
##  Min.   : 4.0   Min.   :  2.00  
##  1st Qu.:12.0   1st Qu.: 26.00  
##  Median :15.0   Median : 36.00  
##  Mean   :15.4   Mean   : 42.98  
##  3rd Qu.:19.0   3rd Qu.: 56.00  
##  Max.   :25.0   Max.   :120.00
fit &lt;- lm(dist ~ speed, data = cars)
fit
## 
## Call:
## lm(formula = dist ~ speed, data = cars)
## 
## Coefficients:
## (Intercept)        speed  
##     -17.579        3.932</code></pre>
</div>
<div id="including-plots" class="section level1">
<h1>Including Plots</h1>
<p>You can also embed plots. See Figure <a href="/blog/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/#fig:pie">1</a> for example:</p>
<pre class="r"><code>par(mar = c(0, 1, 0, 1))
pie(
  c(280, 60, 20),
  c(&#39;Sky&#39;, &#39;Sunny side of pyramid&#39;, &#39;Shady side of pyramid&#39;),
  col = c(&#39;#0292D8&#39;, &#39;#F7EA39&#39;, &#39;#C4B632&#39;),
  init.angle = -50, border = NA
)</code></pre>
<div class="figure"><span style="display:block;" id="fig:pie"></span>
<img src="/blog/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/index_files/figure-html/pie-1.png" alt="A fancy pie chart." width="672" />
<p class="caption">
Figure 1: A fancy pie chart.
</p>
</div>
</div>

          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A second Post</title>
      <link>/blog/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/second-post/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          
            <p>
              <img align="left" hspace="5" src="/blog/second-post/images/randy-tarampi-U2eUlPEKIgU-unsplash_hu01acaed8f5c11a04baff65addea216ee_3421038_0x550_resize_q100_h2_box.webp"/>
            </p>
          
          <p>The quick, brown fox jumps over a lazy dog.</p>
<p>DJs flock by when MTV ax quiz prog.</p>
<p>Junk MTV quiz graced by fox whelps.</p>
<p>Bawds jog, flick quartz, vex nymphs.Waltz, bad nymph, for quick jigs vex!</p>
<p>Fox nymphs grab quick-jived waltz.</p>
<p>Brick quiz whangs jumpy veldt fox.</p>
<p>Bright vixens jump; dozy fowl quack.</p>
<p>Quick wafting zephyrs vex bold Jim.</p>
<p>Quick zephyrs blow, vexing daft Jim.</p>
<p>How quickly daft jumping zebras vex.</p>
<p>Two driven jocks help fax my big quiz.</p>
<p>Quick, Baz, get my woven flax jodhpurs!</p>
<p>&ldquo;Now fax quiz Jack!&rdquo; my brave ghost pled.</p>
<p>Five quacking zephyrs jolt my wax bed.</p>
<p>Flummoxed by job, kvetching W. zaps Iraq.</p>
<p>Cozy sphinx waves quart jug of bad milk.</p>
<p>A very bad quack might jinx zippy fowls.</p>
<p>Few quips galvanized the mock jury box.</p>
<p>Quick brown dogs jump over the lazy fox.</p>
<p>The jay, pig, fox, zebra, and my wolves quack!</p>
<p>Blowzy red vixens fight for a quick jump.</p>
<p>Joaquin Phoenix was gazed by MTV for luck.</p>
<p>A wizard’s job is to vex chumps quickly in fog.</p>
<p>Watch &ldquo;Jeopardy!&rdquo;, Alex Trebek&rsquo;s fun TV quiz game.</p>
<p>Woven silk pyjamas exchanged for blue quartz.Brawny gods just</p>
<hr>
<p>Image: <a href="https://unsplash.com/@randytarampi" title="https://unsplash.com/@randytarampi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://unsplash.com/@randytarampi</a></p>

          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>/blog/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/first-post/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          
            <p>
              <img align="left" hspace="5" src="/blog/first-post/images/paulo-ziemer-oV3zTK7vuP0-unsplash_hu153a88f4e3499ee3625c3f4c16541801_297284_0x550_resize_q100_h2_box.webp"/>
            </p>
          
          <p>One morning, when Gregor Samsa woke from troubled dreams, he found himself transformed in his bed into a horrible vermin. He lay on his armour-like back, and if he lifted his head a little he could see his brown belly, slightly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections. The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked.</p>
<p>&ldquo;What&rsquo;s happened to me?&rdquo; he thought.</p>
<p>It wasn&rsquo;t a dream. His room, a proper human room although a little too small, lay peacefully between its four familiar walls. A collection of textile samples lay spread out on the table - Samsa was a travelling salesman - and above it there hung a picture that he had recently cut out of an illustrated magazine and housed in a nice, gilded frame. It showed a lady fitted out with a fur hat and fur boa who sat upright, raising a heavy fur muff that covered the whole of her lower arm towards the viewer. Gregor then turned to look out the window at the dull weather. Drops</p>
<hr>
<p>Image: <a href="https://unsplash.com/@ziemer" title="https://unsplash.com/@ziemer" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://unsplash.com/@ziemer</a></p>

          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/archive/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <description>
          <![CDATA[ 
          
          <p>Changes</p>

          
          
          
          
          
          ]]>
      </description>


    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>