<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Political Psychology on Vivian Nguyen</title>
    <link>/categories/political-psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Political Psychology on Vivian Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2024, Vivian Nguyen, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/political-psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Concern and Citizen Trust in Different Institutions</title>
      <link>/blog/121621-covid-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/121621-covid-trust/</guid>
      <description>Link Overview Note: I wrote this paper for Government 1372: Political Psychology, a data science in the Harvard Government department. At this point, I was gaining proficiency in R, but had not developed a sophisticated understanding of statistics and causal inference yet. That said, this paper was one of my first large data science projects, and was driven by my newfound passion for applying data science techniques and programming experience to (what I deem to be) relevant real-world problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooperation Strategies</title>
      <link>/blog/091621-cooperation-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/091621-cooperation-strategies/</guid>
      <description>Link Introduction For this week’s blog post, I look at the performance of my six selected cooperation strategies when played in a repetitive, round-robin style tournament and what the results may suggest about cooperation between humans. I select appeaser, foolMeOnce, majorityScrounger, retaliater, titfortat, and winStayer as playing strategies and set them against each other over 100 repeated rounds each.
Link Data Details *File Name: prisoners_dilemma_data.csv
*Source: Shiny app developed by Simon Garnier and edited slightly by the TF team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision-making and Heuristics</title>
      <link>/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/090921-decision-making-heuristics/</guid>
      <description>Link Introduction This is the first Data Exploration task of Fall 2021! Welcome. This week, my classmates of Government 1372 (Political Psychology) and I worked with our in-class survey results to observe how susceptible we are to cognitive biases and discuss how that may affect our decision-making.
Link Data Details *File Name: bias_data.csv
*Source: These data are from last week&amp;rsquo;s in-class survey.
Variable Name Variable Description id Unique ID for each respondent rare_disease_prog From the rare disease problem, the program chosen by the respondent (either &amp;lsquo;Program A&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Program B&amp;rsquo;) rare_disease_cond From the rare disease problem, the framing condition to which the respondent was assigned (either &amp;lsquo;save&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;die&amp;rsquo;) linda From the Linda problem, the option the respondent thought most probable, either &amp;ldquo;teller&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;teller and feminist&amp;rdquo; cab From the cab problem, the respondent&amp;rsquo;s estimate of the probability the car was blue gender One of &amp;ldquo;man&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;woman&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;non-binary&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo; year Year at Harvard college_stats Indicator for whether or not the respondent has taken a college-level statistics course Link The Linda Problem &amp;ldquo;Linda is 31 years old, single, outspoken, and very bright.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
